



# Lelio Campanile

Nationality: Italian

**(**+39) 3478574472

Date of birth: 06/23/1980

Gender: Male

• Address: Viale Lincoln, 5 Department of Mathematics and Physics, 81100 Caserta

(Italy)

#### **SUMMARY**

#### **Short Summary**

I graduated in computer engineering (master's degree). Then I worked as developer freelance. I was starting to develop in different programming language (python, java, c, c++) and as network and system administrator (linux servers and cisco, juniper and mikrotik device).

I love programming in python, and I am a member of Italian Python Association.

Actually I work at Università della Campania "Luigi Vanvitelli"; in the last year I am involved in organising iOS foundation course for my university, in collaboration with Apple, as teacher and as technical reference for that. During this experience I am learning a new way of teaching (CBL Framework) and get me to work with new people from other country.

In my career at University I worked on several project, as the fiber channel university network, the new university website (actually I am a webmaster of this website) and also on the new university's data center.

I support the research activities of the research team of Mauro Iacono, actualy as PhD student.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Full time employee at University

Università degli Studi della Campania "Luigi Vanvitelli" [ 2007 – Current ]

City: Caserta Country: Italy

IT technical employee

- o Computer Network design and PBX administration
- Programming
- System administrator
- Technical support for research activities (Team of Mauro Iacono)

#### Teacher in iOS Foundation Courses

Università degli Studi della Campania "Luigi Vanvitelli" in collaboration with Apple [ 04/2015 – 2019 ]

City: caserta

Teacher/Instructor in many IT courses: web design, web programming, database design, iOS developing

[ 2005 - Current ]

Independent Professional activity as ICT consultant

[ 2004 - 2007 ]

Country: Italy

#### **ENGINEERING LICENSE**

Passed the government exam and licensed as a profession engineer section B [ 2007 ]

Passed the government exam and licensed as a profession engineer section B - Informatics, and enrolled as a member of the Italian Engineering Society with n. 48

Passed the government exam and licensed as a profession engineer section A [ 2019 ]

Passed the government exam and licensed as a profession engineer section A - Informatics (Computer Science), and enrolled as a member of the Italian Engineering Society with n. 4959

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

#### Subject Expert

Università degli Studi della Campania "L. Vanvitelli - Dipartimento di Matematica e Fisica" [ 09/2020 ]

Address: 81100 Caserta (Italy)

#### Ph.D. Student

Università degli Studi della Campania "L. Vanvitelli - Dipartimento di Matematica e Fisica" [ 2018 – Current ]

Address: Caserta (Italy)

# Laurea Magistrale in Ingegneria Informatica (MSc in Computer Engineering)

Università degli Studi Guglielmo Marconi [ 2015 ]

Address: Rome (Italy)

# Laurea Ingegneria Informatica (BSc in Computer Engineering)

Seconda Università degli Studi di Napoli [ 2004 ]

Address: Aversa (CE) (Italy)

# Traineeship on real time rendering using cluster computer

Istituto per il calcolo e le Reti ad Alte Prestazioni del Consiglio Nazionale delle ricerche [ 2004 ]

# Maturità Scientifica (Scientific High School Degree) Liceo "A. Giordano" Venafro Italy

Liceo "A. Giordano" [ 1998 ]

Address: Venafro(IS) (Italy)

#### **COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS**

#### Job-related skills

I get on well with any people. I am a good maker and have a good experience in handling any kind of situation. Because of my previous work experiences I have good variety of skills in computer science. I love programming in python and solve problem with it

#### LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s):

Italian

#### **English**

LISTENING: B2 READING: B2 WRITING: B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION: B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION: B2

#### **PROJECTS**

# **SUN High Speed Networks**

[2010 - 2011]

Member of the "SUN High Speed Network" project team. The project provided fiber optic connection among the "Università della Campania Luigi Vanvitelli" (former "Seconda Università degli Studi di Napoli") sites, distributed on the regional territory.

#### **WIFI SUN**

[2008 - 2009]

Member of the "WIFI SUN" project team. The project provided a wifi network for the students, deployed over 10 sites of the "Università della Campania Luigi Vanvitelli" (former "Seconda Università degli Studi di Napoli")

#### **RIMIC**

[2013 - 2015]

Member of the working team of "RIMIC" (Rete di Interconnessione Multiservizio Interuniversitaria Campana): it provides a wide range of networking services, available on the entire regional territory, can be used as support to research projects and training for all the university of Campania Region. The network is based on fiber optical interconnections and enable the use of the wavelength division multiplexed technology.

#### **University Datacenter**

[2013]

Member of the project team for the design of the new university datacenter ("Università della Campania Luigi Vanvitelli") in Caserta's site

#### **University Website**

[2013]

Member of the working group for the design of the new university website ("Università della Campania Luigi Vanvitelli")

#### **TEACHING AND TRAINING POSITIONS**

### **Computer Science**

[2005 - 2006]

Teacher of Computer Science at "Istituto Tecnico Commerciale Giuseppe Mostati" (High School) of Sant'Antimo under the O.F.I.S. "Operatore per la gestione Aziendale" project.

#### **Matematics**

[2005 - 2006]

Teacher of Matematics at "Istituto Tecnico Commerciale Giuseppe Mostati" (High School) of Sant'Antimo under the O.F.I.S. "Operatore della grande e media distribuzione italiana" project.

# Computer Science: ASP Programming, Data Base and Multimedia Tools

[2006]

Teacher of Computer Science (ASP Programming, Data Base and Multimedia Tools classes) under the "Grandi attrattori culturali – Reggia di Caserta" project.

# **Computer Science - Web Programming**

[ 01/13/2013 - 07/31/2013 ]

Teacher of Computer Science - Web Programming at the training agency "Nuovi Orizzonti" in Aversa (CE) Italy, under the "Tecnico della programmazione e dello sviluppo di siti internet e pagine web" course, ID 3147; authorized by Campania Region with Executive Decree n. 117 of 13 September 2012.

# **Computer Science - Web Programming**

[ 04/01/2016 - 07/31/2016 ]

Teacher of Computer Science - Web Programming at the training agency "Nuovi Orizzonti" in Aversa (CE) Italy, under the "Web Designer" course; authorized by Campania Region with Executive Decree n. 125 of 5 May 2015 and n. 110 of 30 November 2015.

# **Apple iOS Programming - Swift Programming**

[ 04/2015 - 12/2019 ]

Teacher in iOS Foundation Courses in collaboration with Apple at "Università degli Studi della Campania L. Vanvitelli"

#### **Challenge Based Learning**

[ 09/2018 - 12/2018 ]

Teacher of "Challange Based Learning" methodology under the "Formazione Docenti ambito 1 - Challenge Based Learning" PON project at "Istituto Tecnico Professionale Alfonso Casanova" (High School) of Naples

### **Arduino Platform Programming**

[2018 - 2019]

Teacher of Arduino Platform Programming under the "Robotica con Arduino" PON project at "Liceo Scientifico F. Quercia" (High School) of Marcianise (CE) Italy

#### **Augmented Reality**

[2018 - 2019]

Teacher of Augmented Reality under the "Realtà Aumentata" PON project at "Liceo Scientifico F. Quercia" (High School) of Marcianise (CE) Italy

#### **Python Programming**

[ 10/2019 - 12/2019 ]

Teacher of Python Programming under the "Python Web Engineer" course at the training agency "Consorzio Clara" in Naples

#### **Google Angular Programming**

[03/2020]

Teacher of Google Angular Programming at the training agency "Consorzio Clara" in Naples

#### **Advanced Java**

[ 11/2019 - 01/2020 ]

Teacher of Advanced Java Programming at "Gesan s.r.l" in San Nicola La Strada (CE) Italy, under the "ICT TRAINING FOR DEVELOPMENT" project, authorized by Campania Region

#### **Redhat Openshift for Developers**

[ 10/2020 ]

Teacher of Redhat Openshift at the company "BC Soft s.r.l."

#### **ACADEMIC TUTORING AND TEACHING**

#### **Tutoring Fundamentals of Programming - Python Lab**

[2018 - 2019]

Tutor for the Programming Laboratory of Fundamentals of Programming 40 hours in Python programming language - Degree Course of Data Analytics A.A. 2018/2019 - Department of Mathematics and Physics, Università degli Studi della Campania L. Vanvitelli

#### **Fundamentals of Programming - Python Lab**

[2019 - 2020]

Tutor for the Programming Laboratory of Fundamentals of Programming 40 hours in Python programming language - Degree Course of Data Analytics A.A. 2019/2020 - Department of Mathematics and Physics, Università degli Studi della Campania L. Vanvitelli

#### Seminar "Introduction to Programming with Python"

[2019 - 2020]

Seminar "Introduction to Programming with Python" within the course of Programming Fundamentals I - Department of Engineering - Università della Campania L. Vanvitelli A.Y. 2019/2020

# Seminar "Python Data structures"

[2019 - 2020]

Seminar "Python Data structures" within the course of Programming Fundamentals I - Department of Engineering - Università della Campania L. Vanvitelli A.Y. 2019/2020

# Seminar "Python Tools and Library for engineers"

[2019 - 2020]

Seminar "Python Tools and Library for engineers" within the course of Programming Fundamentals I - Department of Engineering - Università della Campania L. Vanvitelli A.Y. 2019/2020

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

# On privacy regulations, smart roads, blockchain and liability insurance: putting technologies at work. [2020]

Lelio Campanile, Mauro Iacono, Alexander H. Levis, Fiammetta Marulli, Michele Mastroianni, On privacy regulations, smart roads, blockchain and liability insurance: putting technologies at work. IEEE Security & Privacy, IEEE, 1540-7993, DOI: (to appear)

#### Performance evaluation of a fog WSN infrastructure for emergency management.

[2020]

Lelio Campanile, Marco Gribaudo, Mauro Iacono, Michele Mastroianni, Performance evaluation of a fog WSN infrastructure for emergency management. Simulation Modelling Practice and Theory, Elsevier, 1569-190X, DOI: (to appear)

# Computer Network Simulation with ns-3: A Systematic Literature Review

[2020]

https://www.mdpi.com/2079-9292/9/2/272

Lelio Campanile, Marco Gribaudo, Mauro Iacono, Fiammetta Marulli, Michele Mastroianni, Computer Network Simulation with ns-3: A Systematic Literature Review. Electronics, MDPI, 9(2), 272, ISSN: 2079-9292, DOI: 10.3390/electronics9020272

#### Modeling performances of an autonomic router running under attack.

[2019]

Lelio Campanile, Marco Gribaudo, Mauro Iacono, Michele Mastroianni, Modeling performances of an autonomic router running under attack. International Journal of Embedded Systems, Inderscience, ISSN: 1741-1076, DOI: (to appear)

# A simulation study on a WSN for emergency management. Communications of the ECMS [2020]

#### **Book Chapter**

Lelio Campanile, Mauro Iacono, Fiammetta Marulli, Michele Mastrioianni, A simulation study on a WSN for emergency management. Communications of the ECMS, Volume 34, Issue 1, June 2020, ISSN: 2522-2414, ISBN: 978-3-937436-68-5, DOI: 10.7148/2020-0384

# Towards the Use of Generative Adversarial Neural Networks to Attack Online Resources. Web, Artificial Intelligence and Network Applications

[2020]

#### **Book Chapter**

Lelio Campanile, Mauro Iacono, Fabio Martinelli, Fiammetta Marulli, Michele Mastroianni, Francesco Mercaldo and Antonella Santone, Towards the Use of Generative Adversarial Neural Networks to Attack Online Resources. Web, Artificial Intelligence and Network Applications, Springer International Publishing, ISBN: 978-3-030-44038-1, DOI: 10.1007/978-3-030-44038-1 81

## Performance Modeling And Analysis Of An Autonomic Router.

[2019]

# **Book Chapter**

Marco Gribaudo, Mauro Iacono, Michele Mastrioianni, Lelio Campanile, Performance Modeling And Analysis Of An Autonomic Router. Communications of ECMS, vol. 33 n. 1, June 2019, ISSN: 2522-2414

# Privacy Regulations Challenges on Data-centric and IoT Systems: A Case Study for Smart Vehicles. [2020]

#### **Conference Paper**

Lelio Campanile, Mauro Iacono, Fiammetta Marulli, Michele Mastroianni, Privacy Regulations Challenges on Data-centric and IoT Systems: A Case Study for Smart Vehicles. IoTBDS 2020, the 5th International Conference on Internet of Things, Big Data and Security, Online Streaming because of the Coronavirus, May 7-9, 2020, DOI: (to appear)

# A WSN energy-aware approach for air pollution monitoring in waste treatment facility site: a case study for landfill monitoring odour .

[2020]

#### **Conference Paper**

Lelio Campanile, Mauro Iacono, Roberta Lotito and Michele Mastroianni, A WSN energy-aware approach for air pollution monitoring in waste treatment facility site: a case study for landfill monitoring odour. IoTBDS 2020, the 5th International Conference on Internet of Things, Big Data and Security, May, 7-9, 2020, Online (because of COVID 19), DOI: (to appear)

# Machine Learning Approaches for Diabetes Classification: Perspectives to Artificial Intelligence Methods Updating

[2020]

# **Conference Paper**

Lelio Campanile, Giuseppe Mainenti, Fiammetta M Carlo Ricciardi, Antonio Valente, Machine Learning Approaches for Diabetes Classification: Perspectives to Artificial Intelligence Methods Updating,IoTBDS 2020, the 5th International Conference on Internet of Things, Big Data and Security, May, 7-9, 2020, Online (because of COVID 19), DOI: (to appear)

On Performance Evaluation of Security Monitoring in Multitenant Cloud Applications.

[2020]

Lelio Campanile, Mauro Iacono, Stefano Marrone, Michele Mastroianni, On Performance Evaluation of Security Monitoring in Multitenant Cloud Applications. Electronic Notes in Theoretical Computer Science, Volume 353, 2020, Pages 107-127, ISSN 1571-0661, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.entcs.2020.09.020.

Quantitative modeling of the behaviour of an autonomic router.

[2020]

#### **Conference Paper**

Lelio Campanile, Marco Gribaudo, Mauro Iacono and Michele Mastroianni, Quantitative modeling of the behaviour of an autonomic router. VALUETOOLS 2019 - 12th EAI International Conference on Performance Evaluation Methodologies and Tools March 13-15, 2019 Universitat de les Illes Balears Palma de Mallorca, Spain, ISBN: 978-1-4503-6596-3, DOI:10.1145/3306309.3306344

#### **CONFERENCES AND SEMINARS**

COMS2 International Conference on Computing Science, Communication and Security

[2021]

**Program Committee** 

IoTDBS2020 the 5th International Conference on Internet of Things, Big Data and Security

[05/2020]

**Program Committee** 

ECMS 2020 - 34th INTERNATIONAL ECMS CONFERENCE ON MODELLING AND SIMULATION

[2020]

Co-Chair Modeling and Simulation for Performance Evaluation of Computer-based Systems MaSPECS

CN2020 Computer Networks 2020

[2020]

**Program Committee** 

INFOCOMP 2020, The Tenth International Conference on Advanced Communications and Computation, MODOPT: Modeling and Optimization

[2020]

**Program Committee** 

SIMUL 2020 The Twelfth International Conference on Advances in System Simulation

[2020]

**Program Committee** 

InfQ2019 9th Workshop of the Italian group on Quantitative Methods in Informatics

[2019]

Local Organizer

### **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

# **Presentations Memberships Certifications**

- o I am a member of Italian Python Association.
- o CCNA Cisco certification (2016)
- o I gave 2 talks in Pycon IT 2017 conference
- o I gave 1 talk in Pycon IT 2018 conference

# **Conferenze Organization**

- o Django Girls Caserta 2019, local organizer
- o PyConIT The Italian Python Conference, volunteer organizer

# **HOBBIES AND INTERESTS**

**New Technology** 

**Swimming**